Guide to the Forestry Club Records, 1962-1976
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Forestry Club records 1962-1976
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. Forestry Club.
0.25 Linear Feet 100 Items
The Forestry Club (sometimes called the Environmental Management Club) was founded in 1962 by graduate students from Duke's Department of Forestry.
Contains correspondence, budgets, memoranda, flyers and negatives related to the activities of the student-run Forestry Club from the years 1962-1976.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Forestry Club Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1977.
Historical Note
The Forestry Club (sometimes called the Environmental Management Club) was founded in 1962 by graduate students in Duke's School of Forestry. The Club organized activities for Forestry students including the Spring Banquet and Christmas tree sale and also published a yearbook starting in 1964-1965. The Club also served as an advocacy group during 1975-1976 amid Duke University's deliberations regarding the phase-out of the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies.
Collection Overview
Contains correspondence, budgets, memoranda and flyers relating to Club activities. Activities include the Spring Banquet and Christmas tree sales, academic meetings, yearbook and speakers series. Also contains photographic negatives of banquets, a club portrait and student projects. A folder of prints was moved to the Photograph Collection. Packets of canceled checks and detailed financial statements were discarded, and the collection was reduced to one Hollinger box.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Forestry Club
Duke University. School of Forestry and Environmental Studies.
Duke University. School of Forestry.
Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.
Related Material
Nicholas School of the Environment records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Tropical Studies (Organization for) Records, 1962-1974.
University Archives, Duke University.
Phytotron Records, 1958-1984.
University Archives, Duke University.
Ellwood S. Harrar Papers, 1928-1975.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1 Box
  - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 1)
  - Donation Possibilities
  - Constitution
  - Social, 1971, 1973
  - Forestry Banquet, 1971
  - Forestry Club Spring Banquet, 1974
  - Memos, undated
  - Yearbook "Taeda", 1963, 1964
  - Forestry Club Christmas Tree Sale, 1969
  - S.A.F. Chapter Possibility
  - Operation Muscle
  - Minutes, 1969-1970
  - Finances, 1969-1972
  - Forestry Who's Who
  - Student Faculty Committee
  - Speaker Series
  - Negatives
  - Correspondence, Memoranda, Clippings, 1974-1975